# 哈喽大家好
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 最近很多粉丝在问过年做点什么菜
Recently, a lot of you guys are asking what we are going to have for the Chinese New Year
# 我觉得过年其实有很多菜可以做
I believe there are many options
# 但是这些菜（我觉得）都没有饺子更合适嘎
But none of these dishes (I personally think) are as good as dumplings
# 嗯
Um
# 今天所以我跟我伯爷一起来做几种这个饺子馅
So today I will make several types of stuffing with my uncle
# 我准备了一些牛肉、虾、（猪）肉、还有鸡蛋
I prepared some beef, shrimps, pork and eggs
# 还有一些其他的辅料
and some minor ingredients
# 我先准备好这些东西
Let me prepare the stuff first
# 来嘛 四伯爷 帮着剥这个虾
Come on, Uncle help me peel the shrimp
# 这个咋个整嘛
How to do it?
# 把虾子的肉剥出来
Take the meat out of the shrimp
# 这样子剥一哈
Like this
# 剥的来不
Are you ok with it?
# 这有啥子剥不来安 逮都脑壳跟它一扯
It is nothing hard. Catch the head and drag it
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 不是的 这个要一哈要剥下来
No, you need to peel both of them together
# 一哈剥下来
Altogether?
# 对 把肉一哈剥下来 不是扯脑壳
Yes, peel the shrimp body part, not dragging the head
# 这个虾如果你们不好剥的话
If you guys have problem with peeling shrimp
# 就拿去冰箱冻一下
You could put them in a refrigerator for a while
# 把它冻硬了就很好剥
The peel is easy to remove when it becomes hard
# 这是一个小技巧
which is a tip
# 哎呀 随便啥子东西还是要熟能生巧 要多干
Aiya, no matter what you are doing, practice makes perfect. Practice more!
# 确实是
That’s true
# 实践出真经
Truth comes from practice
# 好不好剥嘛
Is it easy to peel the shrimp?
# 就是没得好好剥的
Nope
# 我剥都没剥过
I’ve never tried it
# 先把它切成片片儿
First, slice it into pieces
# 然后把它切成颗颗儿
And then cut them into little cubes
# 切成丝 横竖跟它切
cut into shreds
# 是安
Yeah
# 更快都嘛
It’s faster
# 四伯还是懂得起哦
Oh, uncle, you know a lot
# 横着切一下
First cut it in the horizontal direction
# 切了再宰一下
then gathering all of them
# 其实这个饺子馅不需要剁得太细的嘎
actually you don't need to mince the dumpling stuffing too finely
# 太细了反而吃起没得口感的
Otherwise, when you taste it, it will lose a part of texture
# 好了 现在我们这些料已经准备好了
OK now we have finished preparing these ingredients
# 不过这个料太多了
But the amount is too much
# 就一样一样的来
Just do it one by one
# 第一个饺馅儿就是三鲜馅儿
First one is Sanxian stuffing
# 三鲜的哈 四伯爷
Is Sanxian OK, uncle?
# 三鲜的啊
Yeah, Sanxian
# 嗯
Yes
# 三鲜的话
For Sanxian flavor
# 我们先调的就是这个虾
What we make first is the shrimp
# 鲜虾 虾仁 把它剥了壳之后剁碎的
Fresh shrimps. Peel, and then mince it
# 先放一点
Add a little bit
# 然后我切了一些香菇
Then chop some shiitake mushrooms
# 这也是带鲜味的 给它一起放进去
They have the umami taste, let’s add them in together
# 香菇可以多一点
We could add a bit more mushroom
# 然后又加点木耳 这个木耳是水（泡）发的
Then add some wood-ear mushrooms. They are dried, you need to pre-soak them first
# 然后给它剁碎了 新鲜的也可以
And mince them. You could also use fresh wood-ear mushrooms
# 再加一点这个葱 这个小葱
And add some spring onions
# 调味的话都是一样的 就是放点盐
For seasoning, it’s salt
# 然后再放点胡椒粉
and some pepper powder
# 再放点这个生抽酱油
and some light soy sauce
# 酱油可以稍微少一些
Not too much soy sauce
# 然后就给它抓匀
and mix all of them
# 这个虾仁嘛 是新鲜的
The shrimp is fresh
# 加点盐进去给它这样子顺着一个方向搅（搅）
add some salt in it and stir it in same direction
# 它会上劲 有粘性了就可以了
and it will become sticky
# 这个饺子就成了
The dumpling is complete
# 饺子馅就成了
The dumpling stuffing is complete
# 好 这是第一种
This is the first type
# 如果大家喜欢的话还可以加一点这个胡萝卜进去配一下颜色
You guys could also add some carrots to make it more colorful, it’s up to you
# 加胡萝卜的话小孩子就比较喜欢吃
Children tend to like the dumpling with carrots in it
# 它是脆脆的
It is crunchy
# 好第一个（饺子馅）就成了
Well, the first dumpling is out here
# 三鲜就成了
Sanxian stuffing has already been prepared now
# 第二种我们用这个牛肉 做牛肉馅的
Next we’ll make beef stuffing
# 这个是剁好的那个牛里脊肉
It is minced beef tenderloin
# 牛肉馅的饺子放芹菜更好吃
beef with leaf celery is more delicious
# 抓一点芹菜进去 这个牛肉有点多
get some leaf celery in it, the minced beef is a bit too much
# 这个比例的话根据大家自己的喜好来
the portion is up to you guys' personal preferences
# 这个的话是我们本地的韭黄
This is our local jiuhuang (aka Chinese yellow leeks, hotbed chives, ...)
# 加点韭黄进去 增香
Add some jiuhuang for a better flavor
# 然后加点这个马蹄（荸荠）
then add some water chestnut
# 我们这喊啥子安这个
What we call it here?
# 我们这里喊的是“茨瓜儿”
We call it Qianguaer in local dialect
# 这个是削了皮被我剁碎的
I have already peeled and chopped it
# 然后加点这个干香菇
Add some dry shiitake mushroom
# 这个是干香菇 加进去增香的
The dry mushrooms are for flavor enhancement
# 这个馅儿叫做香菇牛肉馅
This stuffing is called “mushroom beef stuffing”
# 调味还是放盐
Salt for seasoning as well
# 这个盐可以稍微重一点点
There could be a bit more salt
# 然后根据口味调一下 加点酱油
Then based on your own flavor, add some soy sauce
# 因为这个牛肉是里脊 是瘦的
Because it is beef tenderloin, it is lean meet
# 所以要加点香油
we need to add some sesame oil
# 滋润一下
for moisturization
# 再加一点胡椒粉
And add some pepper powder
# 好了 抓匀
Okay, mix it
# 就像刚才那个鲜虾（馅）是一样的
Just like how we mixed the shrimp stuffing previously
# 好了 这个抓匀就可以了
Cool, now that is enough
# 下一个是鸡蛋韭菜 （馅）
Next one is egg with Chinese chive filling
# 韭菜鸡蛋馅儿
egg with Chinese chive filling
# 这个鸡蛋我放了6个 煎得
I fried six eggs
# 煎了之后把它弄碎 韭菜就放一半就行了
After it’s cooked, mix it with half of Chinese chive
# 因为韭菜放多了加了盐它会出水
Because if you add too much chive, after adding salt, it produces extra water
# 这个的话就只要韭菜跟鸡蛋就OK
For this stuffing only Chinese chives and eggs are enough
# 同样的是调味 加一点点盐
As for seasoning, a little bit salt
# 这个的话因为煎鸡蛋的时候有放油
You know, because we have already fried it with oil
# 现在只放盐就行了 不用放其他的调料
now we only need to add salt. We don't need any other seasoning
# 同样的然后给它拌匀就可以用来包饺子
mix it finely, then we could use it to make dumplings
# 这样子拌匀就算一个馅儿
After we mix it, we are finished with one more dumpling stuffing
# 现在我们来调第四种
Now it is the fourth dumpling stuffing
# 就是大白菜猪肉馅
It is "Chinese cabbage with pork" stuffing
# 这个大白菜我们要把它处理一下
We need to proccess the cabbage first
# 加一勺盐进去
Add one spoon of salt
# 让它提前脱一下水给它抓一下
To dehydrate the cabbage, and squeeze the water out
# 因为大家都知道大白菜水分比较多
As we all know, cabbages contain a high amount of water
# 如果是说不脱水的话包出来很多水就不好吃了
If we skip this step, then the dumpling will be soggy and untasty
# 四伯爷 你喜欢吃哪种馅儿安
Uncle, which dumpling stuffing do you like?
# 吃哪种馅 我看你整的个个馅我都喜欢吃
Which one? I like everything you made here
# 是不哦
Do you?
# 是啊
Yes
# 你不喜欢吃啥子味道的馅嘛 你说
Tell me what kind of stuffing you don't like
# 那种甜的我就没得好喜欢吃的
I don't like eating sweet dumplings that much
# 好了 现在这个白菜我随便抓两下
Ok, now I’ll squeeze the cabbage for a bit
# 这个水都已经出来了
The water has come out
# 先让它脱一下水
Dehydrate it for a bit
# 免得带到肉里面去 水分它会溢出来
in case the extra water comes into the meat
# 然后加点肉进去
and add some meat
# 肉的话根据你们自身家庭情况来放
you can control the quantity based on your own condition
# 然后还是要调一点酱油
and some soy sauce
# 白菜其实是已经有盐的了
There's already salt in the cabbage
# 调了酱油以后再打一个 （鸡蛋）
after seasoning with soy sauce, crack an egg
# 这点肉打不了一个（鸡蛋）
the meat is not that much for using one egg
# 打半个鸡蛋就可以了
use half of an egg
# 给它做的嫩一些 蛋清就行
to make it more tender, only add egg white
# 同样的再加一点胡椒粉 然后给它拌匀
Same, add some pepper powder, mix it
# 然后给它拌匀
Then mix it up finely
# 好 现在我们来第五种
Now here is the fifth dumpling stuffing
# 第五种的话就是香菇加肉
The fifth is “mushroom with pork”
# 这个是干香菇 泡发好的干香菇 加进去
This is dried shiitake mushroom. Already pre-soaked. Add it in
# 然后这个是新鲜的香菇 相互配合
And this is fresh shiitake mushroom. We use them in combination
# 然后加点这个肉 肥肉
And add some pork, pork fat
# 也不是肥肉 就是五花肉
It's not actually pork fat, it’s pork belly
# 加一点进去
Add some
# 然后这个的话可以配一些胡萝卜配颜色
we could mix some carrots in it as well
# 这个小孩子特别喜欢
Children like it very much
# 再加一点这个马蹄
Add some water chestnuts
# 马蹄吃起来口感脆脆的 很不错
Water chestnut texture is crunchy, which is good
# 同样也是这些调料 盐
Same seasonings. Salt
# 加点盐 加点酱油
Add some salt, add some soy sauce
# 再加点胡椒粉
add some pepper powder
# 这个因为它是自带肥油了 所以就不用再加油了
This one comes with pork fat, we don't need to add more oil
# 好了 现在还有最后一种
Now we have the last one of dumpling stuffing
# 最后一种就随意一点
The last one could be more casual
# 加点这个肉 把剩下的肉全部放进去
add some meat, put all the rest of meat in it
# 然后这个 我们本地的韭黄放一些
We also put some local jiuhuang
# 再放一些韭菜
Add more Chinese chives
# 韭菜放进去香啊
Chinese chives are so fragrant
# 多放点
Add a bit more
# 这个小葱 给它放一半的小葱
Put half of these green onions
# 然后这个马蹄再放一些进去
then add some water chestnuts
# 再放几颗胡萝卜
put some carrots
# 然后再调一下味
seasoning
# 盐
Salt
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 胡椒粉
Pepper powder
# 好 给它抓匀就行了
OK, just mix it finely
# 这个可以根据你们个人口味来
it all depends on your personal preference
# 有的他也加味精 鸡精
You could add MSG or chicken powder
# 但是我觉得没有这个必要
but I don't think that's necessary
# 自己家里面吃的话
for homemade food
# 行了 你看 香得很
that's enough, See, it’s so aromatic
# 你闻哈看嘛
Have a smell
# 是不是 嗯
Does it smell good, Um
# 好了 现在我们这6个馅都已经和完了
Alright, now we have finished all these 6 different dumpling stuffing
# 就是把它已经拌好了
They are all finely mixed